本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：Dr. Monkee 马蒂 米苏 LyraL 跳跳糖 费列罗 西瓜
时间轴：小怡子 潘叔  校对：饿得慌 桃乐  后期：飞飞  总监：丢丢
■
诉 讼 双 雄
第一季 第九集
迈克  小心
No, Mike, stop.
-抱歉  -稳住
- Sorry - Smooth.
你有跳芭蕾舞的潜质
You would made a nice ballerina.
我的身体柔韧性确实比较好
I'm not gonna apologize for my lithe physique, okay?
而且  我高中的时候
And, by the way, I was on the wrestling team
是摔跤队的  所以...
in high school, so...
好笑吗
Is something funny?
我只是在想象你跟别人摔跤的情景
I'm just trying to imagine you fighting someone.
我能弄死你
I would kill you.
-你根本碰不到我  -为什么
- You wouldn't touch me. - Why not?
因为你只会盯着我的紧身裤
Because you'd be too busy staring at me in tights.
我哪有
No, I wouldn't.
你刚才就盯着呢
You're doing it right now.
你又没穿紧身裤
You're not wearing any tights.
我还没穿内裤呢
I'm not wearing any underwear.
我...  你...
I'm--you--
好了  威廉姆斯太太
Okay, so, Mrs. Williams,
等肯尼・沃达斯科那边一结束
We're gonna take you to the deposition
我就带您去取证  好吗
as soon as Kenny Verdasco's finished, all right?
你们真是倒霉
You two draw the short straw?
您说什么
I'm sorry?
你们要把癌症病人聚在一起
You're in charge of corralling the cancer patients.
这可不是什么好差事
It's not the most glamorous duty in the world.
我感觉你们俩配合挺默契的
I supposed you two don't mind working together.
你们在一起多久了
How long you been dating?
不  我有女朋友了
No, no, I'm sort of seeing someone--
你们迟早会在一起的
It's gonna happen sooner or later.
-打扰一下  -抱歉  请稍等
- Excuse me. - Excuse me for a moment.
有什么事吗
Yes?
不好意思  我想我走错了
I'm sorry, I think I'm in the wrong place.
你是来为爱默生石油公司的案子作证的吗
Are you here for the Emerson Petroleum deposition?
不  我是哈维・斯佩克特的老朋友
No, no, I'm an old friend of Harvey Specter's.
这地方太大了  搞得我晕头转向
This place is huge. I just get turned around.
能告诉我怎么走吗
Maybe you can point me in the right direction.
没问题
No problem.
看到那边的门了吗
You just see those doors right there?
穿过去乘电梯
Go through to the elevators,
上两层
Then up two floors,
然后向右转
and then you're gonna take a right,
走到大厅  你就会看到唐娜了
and down the hall, and you'll see Donna.
唐娜  太好了  谢谢你
Donna. Great, thanks.
特拉维斯・坦纳
Travis Tanner.
迈克・罗斯  很高兴见到你
Mike Ross. Good to meet you.
我也是  迈克
Pleasure to meet you, too, Mike.
慢走
Take care.
我和我的妻子艾米丽
My wife Emily and I,
把我在军队挣的钱都攒了下来
we saved every dollar I made in the army,
六年前  我们从纽约的苹果溪
and we moved here from Apple Creek, New York,
搬到这里
six years ago.
我们买了一栋砂石房
We bought a brownstone,
在花园里种了番茄
and planted a tomato garden.
和邻居一起吃烧烤
We had barbecues with the neighbors.
梦想已然成真
It was--it was a dream come true.
但被诊断出肺癌之后
After being diagnosed with lung cancer,
我就无法工作了
I couldn't work anymore.
有时候甚至上楼
I mean, there's times I have difficulty
去看看我女儿都很困难
even going up the stairs to my daughter's room.
你在苹果溪高中念过书  是吧
You attended Apple Creek High School, is that right?
四年都在那里念的
All four years.
你的高中是1985年建的
You high school was built in 1985.
那里以前是做什么的
What was there before?
一座油井
An oil well,
是爱默生石油公司旗下运营的
Owned and operated by Emerson Petroleum.
肯尼  为什么那所高中被关闭了
Now, Kenny, why was the high school shut down?
因为有200个曾经
Because 200 people who taught at
在苹果溪高中任教或上学的人
or attended Apple Creek High were diagnosed
都被诊断出了癌症
with some form of cancer.
抱歉打断一下
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
拉里  给你的
That's for you, Larry.
相信我  挺不错的  看看吧
Trust me, it's good. Use it.
你怎么知道我的名字
How do you know my name?
都在里面呢  拉里
It's all in there, Larry.
你是唐娜吗
Hey, are you Donna?
是的  有何贵干
Yeah, can I help you?
迈克・罗斯让我来找你
Yeah, Mike Ross told me to find you.
图书室里有个原告晕倒了
We were in the library and one of the plaintiffs fainted,
-他们不知所措了  -天呐
- hit their head. - Oh, my gosh.
好吧  我这就去  谢谢你
Okay, I'm on it. Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
你走错了
Wrong office.
哈维  不得不承认  让肯尼・沃达斯科
Harvey, I have to admit, great job making Kenny Verdasco
作为集体诉讼的代表是对的
the face of your class action suit.
我不认识什么肯尼・沃达斯科
I don't know who Kenny Verdasco is.
那你最好弄清楚
Oh, well, you better find out.
你还是先做个自我介绍吧
How about for starters you introduce yourself
不然我就叫保安了  唐娜
or I'm calling security. Donna!
别紧张  我叫特拉维斯・坦纳
Relax, relax. Name's Travis Tanner.
你就是特拉维斯・坦纳
You're Travis Tanner?
你听说过我
You've heard of me.
没有
No.
我是克莱德・麦克菲律所的资深合伙人
I'm a senior partner with Clyde-Macphee.
-我们律所在波士顿  -就算是红袜队
- We're based in Boston. - So are the Red Sox.
波士顿红袜队是美国职棒老牌强队
我也一样不待见
I don't give a shit about them either.
真有趣
That's funny.
可发生在肯尼・沃达斯科身上的事情
You know what's not funny, is what's happening
就没那么有趣了
to Kenny Verdasco.
现在  他们正在问及他的父母
At this moment, they're asking him about his parents,
他们都是重度烟民  不良嗜好啊
both heavy smokers. Nasty habit.
是的  他们每天抽一包
Yes, a pack a day each.
我18岁之前都和他们住在一起
I lived with them till I was 18.
然后他们会问他在服役期间
And then they'll ask how in the army
怎么会接触镍  铬和碳氢化合物
he was exposed to Nickel, Chromium, and hydrocarbons.
我是一名步兵
I was an infantry soldier.
这种事情我别无选择
I didn't have much choice in the matter.
更不用说他在十年前
Not to mention the frivolous lawsuit
对施莱沃连锁杂货店的恶意诉讼
he filed ten years ago against the Shriver Grocery Chain.
我不是恶意的
It wasn't frivolous.
我滑倒时把手肘骨摔碎了
I slipped and shattered my elbow.
他们的工作都做得这么到位了
If they're doing such a great job down there,
那你来找我干什么
what are you doing up here in my office?
因为那些材料是我提供的
'cause I gave them all that.
等他们出来的时候
And when they walk out that door,
我就会来个落井下石
I'm gonna be the one who fires their asses.
那你是来给我打气的吗
So you coming to me for a pep talk?
你很有前途啊  老兄
You're gonna do great, kiddo.
不  爱默生石油公司
No, you see, Emerson Petroleum
马上就要输了
was gonna lose this case.
所以他们来找我挽救局面
So they called me in to fix the situation.
当我打败皮尔逊・哈德曼律所时
And when I beat Pearson Hardman,
不希望有人说
I don't want anyone saying
那是因为他们未派出强将
it was because they didn't send in their best.
抱歉让你失望了
Well, I'm sorry to disappoint you,
这案子是杰西卡・皮尔逊亲自接手的
but Jessica Pearson's handling this case herself.
如果你觉得她还算不上强将
And if you think that she's not the best,
为什么不去找她较量较量呢
why don't you take a run at her and find out?
好了  我明白你的意思
All right, look, I hear what you're saying,
但事情是这样的
But here's the thing.
我知道你清楚我是谁
I know that you know who I am.
我还知道你在大四的时候
And I also know that during your senior year
因为肩伤而无法参加
you missed out on playing in the state championship
州锦标赛
because of your shoulder.
你因为肩伤而无法投球
You can't pitch with a bad shoulder.
结果后来呢
And what do you know,
没有你  他们还是赢了  哈维
they won without you, Harvey.
现在你扪心自问
Now ask yourself something.
你会让杰西卡・皮尔逊
Are you gonna let Jessica Pearson
替你冲锋陷阵吗
play the big game for you, hmm?
有什么好笑的
What's so funny?
我只是在想象
I'm just thinking about
把你打得落花流水的感觉
how I'm gonna enjoy kicking your ass.
那咱们法庭上见
I'll see you in court.
这对我的过去  我的家人  以及所有
It was an attack on my history, my family,
我在乎的事情都是一种打击
everything I care about.
我事先提醒过你
I told you this was coming.
他们在试图激怒你
They're just trying to rattle you.
是啊  他们干得太棒了
Yeah, well, they're doing a hell of a good job.
肯尼  你是我们的主要原告
Kenny, you're our lead plaintiff.
你得保持冷静
You've got to keep your composure.
我不管什么冷静不冷静的
I don't care about composure.
我只想达成和解
I want to make a settlement.
那正是他们想要的
That's exactly what they want.
肯尼  这位是哈维・斯佩克特
Kenny, I'd like you to meet Harvey Specter.
是我的得力助手
He's my right hand.
能不能请你的得力助手告诉我
Can your right hand please tell me why
为什么我们不能请求和解
we shouldn't ask for a settlement?
我并不反对适当地和解
I'm not against settling one bit.
但如果我们主动求和  就处于劣势了
But if we go to them, we're weak.
而他们来找我们的话  我们就有优势
They come to us, we're strong.
哈维说得对
Harvey's right.
他们慢你一步  是因为他们小心谨慎
They came after you because they're running scared.
相信我  他们很快就会来找我们的
Trust me, they'll come to us soon enough.
好吧
Okay.
还有件事
One more thing,
余下的取证工作我会延期进行
I'm gonna postpone the rest of the depositions.
别对其他原告说这些事
Don't tell the rest of the plaintiffs what happened.
这是怎么回事啊
What the hell was that?
请让我接手这件案子
I need you to let me take over this case.
是因为那个打断取证的人吧
The guy that came into my deposition.
-他让你出马  -是的
- He called you out? - Yeah.
-他挺厉害的  -是啊
- He's good. - Yeah.
你觉得我应付不了他吗
You think I can't take him?
他提起了州锦标赛的事
He brought up the state championship.
-你的肩膀  -没错
- Oh, shoulder. - Yeah.
搞定他
Take him.
-小心点  -我会的
- Be careful. - I will.
提起州锦标赛的事
Bringing up state championships,
那真是太坏了
that's just-- that's wrong.
我当时也无能为力
Nothing I wouldn't have done.
谢了
Thanks.
我要你查一下特拉维斯・坦纳的底细
I need you to dig into Travis Tanner.
在哪里就职  就读过哪所学校
Find out where he's worked, where he's gone to school,
打赢过哪些案子
what cases he's won.
这是干嘛  准备为他建个维基百科的词条吗
Why, you thinking about starting a Wikipedia page for him?
这家伙处理案子的方式  我一无所知
I don't know anything about how this guy operates.
在我发起进攻之前  我得彻底了解
And before I make a move, I need to know everything
他是怎么处理案子的
about how this guy operates.
是啊  就为了给他建个维基词条
Right, for his Wikipedia page.
你以为在打热身赛之前  达拉斯小牛队
You think the Mavericks didn't watch game film
不会研究勒布朗的防守进攻方式吗
on LeBron before they played the heat?
勒布朗・詹姆斯: 效力于克里夫兰骑士队
你是哈维・斯佩克特
You're harvey specter.
你不必事先摸清对手底细
You don't need to watch game film.
知道谁会将对手的情况摸得一清二楚吗
Do you know who's watched more game film than anybody?
-不知道  谁  -迈克尔・乔丹
- No. Who? - Michael Jordan.
什么  你怎么知道的
What? How do you know that?
你不信吗  打电话问他
You don't believe me? Let's call him.
-你有迈克尔・乔丹的手机号  -是的
- You have Michael Jordan's phone number. - Yep.
如果我按下了这个按键
If I hit this button right here,
我就打给迈克尔・乔丹了吗
I call Michael Jordan?
电话不就这功能吗
That's kinda how a phone works.
快速拨号按23
Speed dial 23.
-我打了  -打吧
- I'm doing it. - Go for it.
我要问他棒球问题
I'm gonna ask him about baseball.
别问他棒球问题
Do not ask him about baseball.
打...打错了
Wrong--wrong number.
你耍我呢
You're kidding me.
我的天
Oh, my god.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
各位  停下手上的工作
Everybody stop what you're doing,
起立  跟我去图书室
stand up, and follow me in the library.
迈克  你也一样  跟我走
Mike, that goes for you too, up and at 'em.
好的  路易  我很乐意
Yeah, Louis, I'd love to,
但我有些工作要做
but I have some work to do for--
杰西卡陛下不等人
His majesty can't wait.
所有助手现在都跟我去图书室
All associates in the library now.
走吧
Let's go.
有传言说要提前给我们加薪
Rumor is we're getting our annual raises early.
大家都很兴奋
People are freaking out.
很好  哈罗德
That's great, Harold.
我想去弄个纹身
I'm thinking about getting a tattoo.
不加薪你没钱纹吗
You need a raise for that?
我的房租太高了
I'm really overpaying for my apartment.
大家早上好
Good morning, everyone.
大家也许认为召集你们
Many of you seem to think
是要给你们提前加薪
this is about getting your raises early.
-不是  -郁闷
- It isn't. - Suck.
我们发现公司里有违规现象
We've discovered a breach at the firm.
高度机密的证人名录外泄给了我们的对手
A confidential witness list was leaked to a rival firm,
韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所
Wakefield-Cady.
也很有可能
Now it's entirely possible
这只是无心之过
that this was an honest mistake.
如果是那样  我们希望当事人
If so, we urge the responsible party
能主动坦白
to come forward.
如果不是  我们很快会彻查清楚
If not, we'll find out soon enough.
不管怎样
Either way,
我们会把这件事查个水落石出
we will get to the bottom of this.
路易
Louis.
杰西卡觉得这只是犯错
Jessica seems to think a mistake's been made.
我不觉得
I don't believe so.
我也不认为这关乎道德
I also don't believe this is a matter of ethics.
而是忠诚与否
It's a matter of loyalty.
这个房间里的某个人背叛了我们大家
Someone in this room has betrayed us all,
我对此人深痛恶觉
and it makes me sick.
而消息走漏给了韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所那些小人
The fact that it went to those holier-than-thou pricks
你们知道吗  这使我更加痛恨此人
at Wakefield-Cady, you know what, that makes me sicker.
你们在一起工作
Now, you all work together,
在同一战线  并肩作战
in the trenches, shoulder-to-shoulder,
你们当中肯定有人知道是谁干的
which means one of you must know who did this.
如果你们知道是谁走漏的消息
Now if y'all harbor knowledge of the perpetrator
而不揭发的话
and do not turn him in,
你们就和他一样可恶
You're as bad as the perpetrator himself,
最终你们将一同卷铺盖走人
you along with the perpetrator will be fired.
他在模仿小布什
He's doing George W. Bush.
各位  与我们为敌或为友  就在一念之间
You're either with us or against us, folks.
他说话像小布什  但看起来像切尼
He sounds like bush, but he looks just like Cheney.
理查德・布鲁斯・切尼:美国前副总统
你有话要说吗  哈罗德
You got something to tell me, Harold?
没有吗
No?
不想谈一下你在我办公室里
Not that dermatological problem
谈过的皮肤病的问题吗
that you were talking about earlier in my office?
-不想谈那个吗  -不
- No, not that one? - No.
为了表示我的决心
To show you how serious I am,
我有奖励政策
I have an incentive.
揭发背叛者的人
Whoever turns this traitor in
将得到一万美元作为奖励
receives $10,000.
不客气
You're welcome.
回去继续工作吧
Feel free to go back to work.
一万美元  能纹好大一个纹身了吧
$10,000, that's a big tattoo.
是啊  巨大无比
Yeah, it'd be huge.
什么事
Why?
-路易说有个...  -不关我的事
- Louis, there was a-- - I don't care.
关于特拉维斯・坦纳  告诉我你都查到些什么
Tell me what you learned about Travis Tanner.
都在这里面了
It's all in there.
特拉维斯・坦纳曾就读耶鲁大学
Travis Tanner went to Yale,
法学本科  成绩优异
undergrad in law, honors in both.
他还是青年网球冠军
He was a junior tennis champion.
网球啊  就和路易一样
Tennis. Just like Louis.
是啊  他在大学也打网球的
Yeah, he played in college too.
-天呐  -更重要的是
- Oh, my god. - More importantly,
他是克莱德・麦克菲律所史上最年轻的资深合伙人
he was the youngest senior partner at Clyde-Macphee.
这家伙的履历无懈可击
This guy's record is off the charts.
是吗
Really?
他擅长代理集体诉讼案
he specializes in breaking class action lawsuits.
哈里斯烟草案  贝尔农药案
Harris Tobacco, Bell Pesticide,
格夫泰克证券案  统统拿下
Gravtech Securities, he broke 'em all.
那我怎么从未听说过他
How come I've never heard of him?
很显然  他不愿接受大众关注
Evidently, he doesn't like to take public credit.
为人低调  也不接受采访
Stays off the radar, he avoids the press.
我也是查看法庭记录才知道这些的
I only found this stuff by looking through court records.
那就说得通了
Now it makes sense.
什么
What?
他觉得我应该认识他
Why he thinks I know him.
他以为其他律师
I know those other attorneys.
会向我提起他
He thinks they've told me about him.
-他们没提起过吗  -没有
- They never did? - No.
-为什么  -因为他们全都败诉于他
- Why not? - Because he beat them.
这家伙挺难对付的嘛
This guy's kind of a badass.
要我帮你要他的签名吗
You want me to get you an autograph?
不用  只是对我们的敌人表示下崇敬
No, I'm just respecting our foe.
-敌人  -《孙子兵法》里说的
- Foe? - It's from The Art of War.
不是吗
No?
不是  听着  我得知道
No, look, I need to know
他打赢的那些案子和我们这起案子的区别
how those other cases are different from ours.
他打赢的那些案子分布在不同地区
Those other cases were spread out
经济基础和社会背景均不相同
geographically, economically, socially.
而我们的案子发生在一个小镇的一所学校里
Ours is in a single town, a single school
外加一群弱势的原告
with a single cluster of plaintiffs.
很好
That's good.
那个网球混账特拉维斯・坦纳来电
That tennis-playing douchebag Travis Tanner's on the phone.
你知道我一直在听你说话
You know I listen.
特拉维斯  有什么能为你效劳吗
Travis, what can I do for you?
我很乐意谈一下案子的事
Yeah, I'm happy to discuss the case,
不过有个条件
on one condition.
我们得在苹果溪高中碰个头
You're gonna meet me at Apple Creek High School.
一小时候后见
See you in an hour.
为什么要在那见面
Why do you want to meet there?
因为那里是事发地
Because that's ground zero.
我要在谈判时  利用那所学校的遭遇
And I want the emotion of that school under my feet
掌握谈判全局
when I negotiate.
我还以为你反对打情感牌
I thought you were against emotions.
我反对抒发情感
I'm against having emotions,
而不是利用情感
not against using them.
我还以为我们是哥们
Come on, I thought we were homies.
吉米  我没泄露过情报
Jimmy, I didn't leak anything.
我记得你说过
You know, I remember you said
你讨厌路易・利特  而且对于你是否
you hated Louis Litt and you were second-guessing
要继续干律师这一行也犹豫不决
your decision to become a lawyer.
那是在六杯甜酒下肚的情况下私下告诉你的
I told you that in confidence over six cosmopolitans.
那也不代表你不是叛徒啊
It doesn't mean you're not the guy.
哈罗德  不是吧  你喝甜酒吗
Harold, really? You drink cosmopolitans?
别再喝了  除非你和女孩们在一块
Stop doing that unless you're with girls,
而你也没那机会了  还有  吉米
which you never are. And, Jimmy,
你没搞错吧  竟然冲着哈罗德来了
are you kidding me, going after Harold?
你怎么知道不是他干的
What, how do you know he didn't do it?
我们怎么知道不是你干的呢
How do we know you didn't do it?
也许你才是始作俑者吧
Maybe you're the guy.
我的天  各位  这太荒谬了
Oh, my god, guys, this is ridiculous.
你们难道就不认为
All right, has it occurred to any of you
这也许是对我们的考验吗
that maybe this is all just a big test?
有所隐瞒的人才会这么说吧
Spoken like a person with something to hide.
路易强调的是忠诚
Louis was talking about loyalty.
也许只是检验我们忠诚与否的一个测试
Maybe this is just some test to see how loyal we are
我们不必自相残杀
by not turning on each other.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
杰西卡从来都不会用这招的
Jessica would never play along with something like that.
就算这不是要检验我们
Even if it's not a test,
这是律师办公室  不是自相残杀的世界
this is a law office, not Lord of the Flies.
大家继续工作吧
Everybody get back to work.
这些是加路斯卡一案的摘要吗
Are these the Galusska briefs?
伙计们  路易一直在问我们要这个
You guys, Louis has been hounding us for these.
为什么没人拿去给他
Why hasn't anyone taken them to him?
你们当真吗
Are you serious?
你们怕他
Wow. You're scared of him.
他是路易・利特  他又不是达斯・维德
He's Louis Litt, he's not Darth Vader.
达斯・维德: 《星球大战》中西斯黑暗尊主
这才叫勇气可嘉  吉米  学着点
This is what courage looks like. Jimmy, pay attention.
拜托
Please.
路易  加路斯卡一案的摘要
Louis, the Galusska briefs.
抱歉  送晚了
Sorry they're late.
谢谢了  迈克・罗斯
Hmm, Thank you, Mr. Mike Ross.
-确定你准备好了吗  -我不是已经来了嘛
- Sure you're ready for this? - I'm here, aren't I?
我查过你的底细  你很难捉摸啊
I've been looking into you. You're an elusive man.
你要是行业里的老大
Yeah, well, when you're number one,
就不需要再到处宣传你的战绩了  哈维
you don't need to broadcast your victories, Harvey.
真有意思  在我家乡
That's funny. Where I come from,
老大通常不会去挑战老二
number one doesn't usually challenge number two to a fight.
这个学校是苹果溪的骄傲
This school was Apple Creek's pride.
家长们放心将孩子送到这里
Parents felt safe sending their children here,
老师们安心在这里教书
and teachers felt safe teaching here.
你知道苹果溪高中现在是什么样子吗
You know what Apple Creek High School is now?
小镇郊区的几辆拖车
A bunch of trailers on the outskirts of town.
这都是因为三十年前你的客户
All because 30 years ago your clients
未能封住油井  导致镇民全都得了癌症
failed to cap an oil well and gave them all cancer.
你看到周围的输电线了吗
You see all these power lines around here?
它们在整个小镇纵横交错
They crisscross the entire town.
那条路往前两公里  是油漆厂
Two miles down that road, paint factory.
这里还有微波发射塔
You got a microwave tower.
而眼前这片草地
And all this grass that you see?
近二十年内  每周都会喷洒杀虫剂
It's been treated with pesticide every week for 20 years.
你说是我们的过错  我说你们错了
You say it's our fault. I say you're wrong.
那个办公室的主人  米奇・罗斯沃尔
That office, Mitch Rosewall,
足球教练  得了脑癌
soccer coach, brain cancer.
图书馆的莫尼卡・多德  志愿者
Library, Monica Dodd, volunteer.
她在这里好多年了  得了胃癌
She ran it for years. Stomach cancer.
他们上个月都死了
They both died last month,
而显然他们不是因为杀虫剂而死的
and they sure as hell didn't die from pesticide.
-你有证据吗  -如果上庭
- Can you prove it? - If we go to trial,
就不是提供证据那么简单了
it won't be about proving anything.
那将会牵涉到莫妮卡  米奇和肯尼
It'll be about Monica, Mitch, and Kenny,
到时你绝无胜算
and you won't stand a chance.
太有趣了  哈维
Ah, this is fun, Harvey.
我只能满怀歉意地说  不得不在法庭见了
I'm just sorry to say that we won't get to do this in court.
虽然违背我意  但是爱默生想要和解
Against my advice, Emerson wants to settle.
你耍我吧
You're kidding me.
说了这么多  你却想要和解
After all this, you want to settle.
没耍你  刚刚那些话算是我的说明
No, I don't, but those are my instructions.
到此为止
Call it a draw.
去你的
迈克  到肯尼家去
Mike, get over to Kenny's house.
坦纳想要逼他妥协
Tanner's gonna try and make him cave.
我一收到消息就来了
I came as soon as I got the message.
肯尼
Kenny.
我是哈维・斯佩克特
It's Harvey Specter.
特拉维斯・坦纳在吗  我刚刚还和他在一起
Was Travis Tanner here? I was just with him.
他不会比我先到太久
He couldn't have beaten me by much.
宝贝  你先进屋好吗
Sweetie, why don't you go inside, okay, baby?
来的不是他
No, it wasn't him.
是其他人  他不肯说自己的名字
It was someone else. He wouldn't tell me his name.
他说是皮尔逊・哈德曼律所的  我就让他进屋了
He said he was with Pearson-Hardman, so I let him in.
他提到坦纳的名字了吗
Did he mention Tanner's name?
没有  但是显然他为那人工作
No, but it was obvious that's who he worked for.
他说很快会给我和其他原告
He said me and the other plaintiffs
提供和解条件
were gonna get a settlement offer soon.
-还有吗  -他说如果我们不接受
- What else? - He said if we don't take it,
他们不会放过我们的
that they're gonna go after us.
他们有我们的把柄
That they have dirt on everyone.
他提到伊娃・威廉一家
He mentioned Eva Williams'
因公共场所醉酒闹事而被捕
arrest for public intoxication,
伯尼・拉瑟福德在大学时
Bernie Rutherford's shoplifting arrest
-因入店盗窃而被捕  -那是刑事恐吓
- when he was in college. - That's criminal intimidation.
如果他们想要跟我过不去  没关系
If they want to go after me, that's fine.
我可以应付
I can handle it.
但是其他人  我不知道他们行不行
But the others, I don't know if they can.
你必须要坚强  肯尼
You have to stay strong, Kenny.
你一旦放弃  一切都会分崩离析
You cave, everything falls apart.
还有一个问题  那家伙长什么样
One more thing, what did this guy look like?
大概是中等身材
I don't know, he was average height,
棕发褐眼
brown hair, brown eyes.
谢了
Thanks.
知道那家伙是谁吗
So figuring out who this guy is?
不知道  我们找不到他的
No. We'll never find him.
你怎么知道坦纳会对肯尼下手
How'd you know  was going after Kenny?
如果我是那种不择手段的人
'Cause if I was the type to go out of bounds,
我一定会那么做
that's exactly what I'd do.
-你不是  -不是
- You're not? - No.
下一步要做什么
So what's our next move?
搬救兵
I'm calling in reinforcements.
什么意思
What do you mean?
既然坦纳派人去恐吓肯尼
If Tanner sent a guy to intimidate Kenny,
他肯定还有其它阴谋诡计
he's got something else up his sleeve,
我想知道到底是什么
and I want to know what it is.
怎么了
What?
没什么  你俩就像一个硬币的正反面
Nothing, you guys are like two sides of the same coin.
你说什么  他是另一个我吗
What are you saying, he's another me?
没人能和我媲美
No one is another me.
你告诉唐娜我是另一个你
I mean, you told Donna I was another you.
我从没这么说
I never said that.
你说你在寻找另一个你
You said you were looking for another you,
然后你就聘用了我
and then you hired me.
明白其中的联系了吗
So see how that works?
逻辑
Logic.
迈克跟我走  立刻去我办公室
Mike, let's go. In my office now.
该死  迈克
Oh, damn, Mike.
告诉我你没走漏文件信息  伙计
Tell me you didn't leak the documents, man.
你是我们的本尼迪克特・阿诺德吗
Are you our Benedict Arnold?
本尼迪克特・阿诺德  美国革命家和军事家  与英国人达成秘密协议将纽约州的西点要塞出卖给英方
本尼迪克特・阿诺德  不错的引用
Benedict Arnold, nice reference.
你又在帮你念中学的女友
You helping your high school girlfriend
做家庭作业了吗
with her homework again?
这么说太不厚道了  迈克
Okay, not cool, Mike.
你知道达拉在念社区大学
You know Darla's in community college.
我不知道有什么好笑的  哈罗德
I don't even know why you laughing, Harold.
你都没女人
You don't have a chick.
她成年了
She's of age.
我太为你骄傲了  迈克
I am so very proud of you, Mike.
你现在别抓着我就更好了
Wow, I really wish you weren't touching me right now.
你就是忠心的典范啊
You are what loyalty looks like.
你找出了向韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所
You rooted out the person responsible
泄露证人名单的叛徒
for leaking the witness list to Wakefield-Cady.
路易  我完全不知你所云
Louis, I have no idea what you're talking about.
你将证据藏在加路斯卡一案的摘要里
It was almost cute how you hid the evidence
真是太可爱了
in the Galusska briefs.
搞得像是你不想要接受表扬
Like you didn't want to take the credit.
什么  路易  我什么也没藏
What? Louis, I didn't hide anything.
别担心  没人会给你贴上告密者的标签
Don't worry, no one's gonna label you a snitch.
告密者
Snitch?
我们根本没想到要检查传真机
We didn't even think to check the fax machines.
太聪明了
That was brilliant.
这份名单正是从本公司发出的
The list was sent from right here in this firm.
这是三天前发出的一份传真提交表格的复印件
This is a copy of a fax submission form sent from three days ago.
这不能用来指证任何人
This doesn't implicate anybody.
那是机要人员密码
That's the confidential employee code.
她一定不知道机器会自动记下
She must not have known that the machine recorded it.
她
She?
等等  为什么我被停职了
Wait, why am I being suspended?
我没有泄露任何文件
I didn't leak any documents.
谁跟路易说是我做的
Who told Louis I did this?
请走吧
Let's go please.
-这边走  -不  不  路易
- This way. - No, no, no, Louis.
你不能这样  我没出卖瑞秋
You have to stop this. I didn't turn Rachel in.
你没想真心告发谁
That's so sweet how you didn't really mean to
真是太体贴了  等下  迈克  站住
hand someone in. Wait, Mike, stop.
你做了件大好事
You did a great thing.
正因为这件好事
And because of that great thing,
一万美金  别一下子花光了
$10,000, and don't spend it in one place.
你说  谢谢你  路易
You say, "Thank you, Louis."
然后  我说  "不客气  迈克"
And then, "You're welcome, Mike."
-瑞秋  -我不想和你说话
- Rachel. - I don't want to talk to you.
-别这样  -既然你不想这样
- Hey, come on. - You want "Come on"?
-为什么要那样对我  -我什么也没做
- Why would you do that to me? - I didn't do anything to you.
我没有传真那份该死的名单
I didn't fax that goddamn list.
我也没出卖你
And I didn't turn you in.
那为什么我被停职了  迈克
Then why was I just suspended, Mike?
我只知道  我给了路易一摞摘要
All I know is that I gave Louis a stack of briefs
里面有印着你机要密码的传真
and there was some fax with your confidential code on it.
如果我要泄露公司文件
Do you think that if I was gonna leak firm documents,
我会笨到在传真上用自己的密码吗
I'd be dumb enough to fax them with my own code?
我知道你不会
No, I don't,
但是不管是谁做的  一定栽赃给了你
but whoever did this must have framed you.
是啊  他成功了
Yeah, well, it worked.
瑞秋  听着  他们会对此展开调查的
Rachel, look, you just-- they're gonna investigate this.
他们会还你清白的  你知道的
They're gonna clear your name, you know that.
我在那里工作了五年
I've worked there for five years,
他们就这么对待我
and this is how they treat me?
我被停职了  迈克
I'm suspended, Mike.
很有可能还会被解雇
I'm probably gonna be fired.
我该告他们的
I should sue them.
别那么冲动好吗
Okay, let's not do anything rash, okay?
这不是冲动  我只是要为自己讨个公道
It's not rash. It's standing up for myself.
瑞秋  你
Rachel, you--
你反应过度了
You're over-react--
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你该不会恰好知道什么葡萄酒
You wouldn't happen to know what sort of wine
配鲜橙h鸭最好吧
pairs well with a duck l'orange, would you?
试试全果味的吧
Try something with a full fruit flavor,
比如赤霞珠
like a cabernet sauvignon.
赤霞珠对我来说有点清淡
Eh, sauvignons are a little bit oaky for my palate.
这儿正好有篇文章
This article right here
是关于黑比诺葡萄酒重获青睐的
is all about the resurgence of pinot noir.
你知道  你完全能在大庭广众下付我钱
You know, you could just pay me right out in public.
可是那样我就不像007了
But then I wouldn't feel like James Bond.
这么说的话  我又像谁呢
Oh, who's that make me?
普茜・葛罗尔[007之金手指中的邦女郎]
Pussy Galore.
奥科托普茜[007之八爪女的邦女郎]
Octopussy?
行了  哈维
That's enough, Harvey.
你给我带了什么来
What do you have for me?
没什么  表面上看坦纳没什么问题
Nothing. On paper, Tanner's clean.
他也许不按规矩办事  但没留下证据
He may break the rules, but he covers his tracks.
你可从没两手空空地来找过我
You've never come up empty for me before.
这次也不例外
I didn't this time either.
坦纳在沃尔多夫酒店订了间会议室
Tanner booked a conference room
明天中午用
at the Waldorf tomorrow at noon.
分而治之  各个击破
Divide and conquer.
他要叫来所有原告
He's gonna gather my plaintiffs,
吓唬他们  然后给他们一个极低的报价
scare them, and then give them a lowball offer.
但这么做是违法的
And that's illegal.
怎么了
What?
你让我为你做过许多事
You've used me for a lot of things.
但你从没让我
You've never asked me to investigate
去调查另一个律师
another attorney before.
这家伙有点本事
This guy's good.
如果他给你的原告打电话
If he called your plaintiffs,
我能搞到他的通话记录来证明这一点
I can get his phone records to prove it.
他不会亲自给他们打电话的
He didn't make those calls himself.
他明天也不会去沃尔多夫酒店
He's not gonna be at the Waldorf either tomorrow.
不过我会去
But I will.
唐娜  你能不能告诉我
Donna, can you tell me
路易说的瑞秋用来
about these confidential employee codes
把证人名单传真到韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所的
that Louis says Rachel used to fax the witness list
员工个人代码是怎么回事
over to Wakefield-Cady?
我在午饭前有很多事要做
I have a thousand things to do before lunch.
拉着年幼迈克的手过马路
Hold Mike's hand while he crosses the street,
可不在其中
not one of them.
唐娜  这次是为了瑞秋
Donna, this one's for Rachel.
你需要什么
What do you need?
我知道我们用账单代码来向客户收费
I know we use the billing codes to charge the clients,
但员工个人代码是干嘛用的
but what do we use the employee codes for?
那是一些特殊的代码
They're special codes for when you need to use
让你可以用公司的资源来办私事
the firm's resources for personal reasons.
我们还能这么做
We can do that?
-你不行  但是瑞秋可以  -为什么
- You can't, but Rachel can. - Why?
因为对公司来说  一个入职五年的
Because a fifth-year paralegal
律师助理比一个刚入行的助理律师更重要
is more valuable to the firm than a first-year associate.
好吧  那你有个人代码吗
Okay, so do you have a personal code?
-我有两个  -你是从哪儿弄到的
- I have two. - So where do you get them?
是由I.T.部门发给我们的
They're generated by the I.T. Department.
我们还有I.T.部门
We have an I.T. Department?
这些电脑又不会自己运行
The computers don't run themselves.
至少在天网变活跃之前不会
At least until skynet goes active.
莎拉・康纳说的[终结者2中男主的母亲]
Sarah Connor.
太烂了
No.
-糗了  我得再练练  -太烂了
- No, I'll work on that. - Really bad.
什么
What?
你好  打扰一下  我想找本杰明
Uh, hi, excuse me. I'm looking for Benjamin.
哥就是
You found him.
那太好了  我是迈克・罗斯
Oh, great, I'm Mike Ross.
我们刚刚通过电话
We just spoke on the phone.
老天  这地方就像《银河战星》里的航母
Man, this place is like Battlestar Galactica.
《银河战星》  美国科幻电视连续剧
你们把机器人放在哪儿
Where do you guys keep the cylons?
皮尔逊・哈德曼律所照顾我们的生意
Pearson-Hardman takes care of us
因为我们二十四小时随传随到
because we're on call 24/7.
如果服务器出现故障
If a server goes down
或是哪个合伙人的电脑出了问题
or a partner's computer crashes,
这是生死攸关的事情
people die.
这有点夸张了  你不觉得吗  本
That's a little dramatic, don't you think, Ben?
叫我本杰明
It's Benjamin.
我敢说你肯定不喜欢别人叫你迈克
I'm sure you don't like it when people call you Mike.
事实上  我更喜欢别人叫我迈克
Actually, I prefer Mike.
好吧  迈克  六个月前我在
Well, Mike, six months ago
康纳利・怀特律所  他们的网络故障
I was at Connolly White, the network went haywire,
我们当时正在做一个价值四亿美元的
and we were in a breach of contract litigation
违约诉讼
worth $400 million.
需要在一小时内排除故障
They needed it fixed in an hour.
大家都认为这是不可能的
No one thought it could be done.
但是我只用了二十三分钟就使之起死回生
I had the network up and running again in 23 minutes.
你觉得这够夸张不
Is that dramatic enough for you?
哇  你就像是现实中的扎克伯格
Wow, you're like a regular Zuckerberg.
扎克伯格[美国Facebook创始人]
Z-zuckerberg?
扎克伯格那技术给我打下手都不够
Zuckerberg couldn't code his way out of a paper bag.
你打电话是为了员工个人代码的事
You called about the employee codes.
你今年刚来  没有代码  不好意思
You're a first year. You can't have one, sorry.
好吧  其实  我也不需要
Okay, well, I don't need one.
我只想知道有没有可能
I just want to know if it's possible
有人能拿到别人的代码
for someone to gain access to somebody else's code.
当然  只有一个人可以  就是我
Sure. For one person, me.
我可以拿到所有人的代码
I have access to all of the codes.
好吧  那在你为这里工作的短暂时间里
Okay, so in your short tenure here,
有没有人曾从你这里
has anyone ever asked you for access
拿到过别人的代码
to someone else's code?
有过一回  就在上个礼拜
Once. Last week.
-谁  -我不能告诉你
- Who? - I can't tell you that.
为什么不能
Why not?
I.T.员工与客户保密协议
I.T. Officer/Client Privilege.
有这玩意儿吗  本
Does that even exist, Ben?
我心里有
It does in here.
好吧  本  我们来打个赌
All right, Ben, why don't we make a bet?
我想你是说要下个注  迈克
I think you mean a wager, Michael.
对  没错
Yeah, sure.
如果我能说对这张纸上的所有数字
I'm gonna tell you every single number on this piece of paper,
你就告诉我那个人是谁
and you're gonna give me that name.
如果你说错了呢
And if you can't?
那我就给你这张一万美元的支票
Then I'm gonna give you this check for 10 grand.
你说错一个数字  一个逗号或是小数点
You get one number, one comma, one decimal point wrong,
那钱就归我了
and that money is mine.
对了  要是我赢了
Oh, and when I win,
我还要一台那样的电脑
I'll also take one of those computers.
还有  告诉你
And for the record,
那上面一个逗号也没有
there's not a single comma on there.
你准备好了没
You ready?
瑞秋  我是迈克
Rachel, it's Mike.
我查出是谁把名单泄露给韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所了
I figured out who leaked the list to Wakefield-Cady.
是路易干的  给我回电话
It was Louis. Call me back.
你好  我是瑞秋・赞恩  我来面试
Hi, I'm Rachel Zane. I'm here for my job interview.
-欢迎来到韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所  -谢谢
- Welcome to Wakefield-Cady. - Thank you.
好  我们进去后
Okay, as soon as we get inside
我要你找到跟你谈过话的所有原告
I need you to find every plaintiff you interviewed
告诉他们那人把找他们来是一种欺诈行为
and tell them they're here under false pretenses.
-没问题  -肯尼会在这儿跟我们碰头
- Done. - Kenny's meeting us here.
我们需要他来辨认那个去找他的人
We need him to identify the man who came to see him,
然后就等着他接近
and we're gonna wait for that guy to approach
我们的任一个原告
any of our plaintiffs.
如果我们能证明那个人和坦纳有联系
And if we connect that guy to Tanner,
我们就可以告他刑事恐吓
then we have him on criminal intimidation.
这样一来  爱默生石油公司只能选择和解
And Emerson Petroleum will have no choice but to settle.
你好  肯尼  见到你很高兴
Hey, Kenny. Good to see you.
今天有好戏看了
This is gonna be fun.
你说的没错
You were right.
他把所有人都叫来了
He called every one of them.
看见去找你的那人了吗
You see the guy?
没有
No.
好好找找
Start looking.
等一下
Hey, wait a minute.
威廉姆斯夫人  还记得我吗
Mrs. Williams, do you remember me?
我是迈克・罗斯  律所的员工
I'm Mike Ross, from the office.
我记得你
I remember you.
我能问问您您今天怎么会来这儿吗
Do you mind if I ask you what you're doing here today?
我们被请来听取和解的报价
We were invited to come and hear a settlement offer.
这样啊
Really?
不好意思  我得走开一会儿
Um, excuse me just for a minute.
他亲自来了
He came here himself.
他犯了个大错
Big mistake.
虽然我不想搞砸你的午餐
Sorry to ruin your little brunch,
但我想你很清楚
but I think you know damn well
你私下联络我的委托人是违法的
that you can't legally address my clients.
我来这儿只是为了喝点果汁
Hey, I just came for the juice.
纯果汁哦
Pulp free.
我知道我不能直接跟你的委托人谈话
I know I can't talk to your clients directly.
不过谢天谢地你也在这儿  哈维
But thank God you're here, Harv.
因为我可以跟你谈话
Because what I can do is I can talk to you.
哈维  爱默生石油公司
Harvey, Emerson Petroleum
会赔偿你的每一位委托人两万五千美元
is offering $25,000 to each and every one of your clients.
如果他们不接受的话
They don't take that,
这场官司会持续好几年
this trial stretches out for years.
盘问会毫不留情
Cross-examinations will be brutal.
但是如果你们肯接受
You take our settlement,
整个事情明天就雨过天晴了
and this whole thing will be gone tomorrow.
如果你的任何一位委托人
Now if any of your clients
想联系我的话
want to get in touch with me,
这是我的电话号码
here's my number.
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross.
哈维
Harvey.
把那号码擦了
Erase that number.
出来混总是要还的  这你还是知道的吧
You're not gonna get away with what you're doing.
这你心里清楚吧
You know that, right?
怎么了
What?
我不过是高声跟你说话而已
I just addressed you with a raised voice.
我耳朵有时不太灵光
Sometimes my ears aren't so good.
要是别人听到我的话  那抱歉了  哈维
If other people heard me, I apologize, Harvey.
我很高兴你的足智多谋
I'm just glad you were smart enough
帮你查到我预订了沃尔多夫酒店
to figure out I booked the Waldorf.
我得接这个电话
Mmm, I think I need to take this.
我想是你哪位客户
I'm guessing it's one of your clients
打算接受我的和解条款了
wanting to take my settlement offer.
你好
Hello.
坦纳  我要追你到天涯海角
Tanner. I'm coming after you.
没错  我有你电话
Oh, I got your number.
原告都害怕了
Plaintiffs are scared.
他们都考虑要接受坦纳的低额条款
They're talking about accepting Tanner's lowball offer.
这道闸门一开  我们将溃不成军
Those floodgates open and we're done.
所以我去找了克拉克森
That's why I went to go see Clarkson.
法律财务部的那个吗
The legal finance guys?
如果我们能帮原告贷到款
If we can get our plaintiffs a loan
资助他们将来的诉讼费用
against a future jury award,
闸门就会关上  也为我们赢得时间
it'll close the floodgates and buy us more time.
这种贷款可不是小数目  哈维
Those loans aren't cheap, Harvey.
总比他们为了点小钱就答应和解强
Well, it's better than settling for pennies on the dollar.
-那去办吧  -我试过了
- Then do it. - I tried,
但没有担保金他们一毛不拔
but they won't give us anything without collateral.
他们觉得你赢不了
They don't think you can win.
庸人之见
They're wrong.
这话我爱听
That's what I like to hear.
我需要一百万才能拿到贷款
I need a million dollars to get that loan.
你是想公司掏钱吗
Are you talking about firm money?
-正是  -门都没有
- Yeah. - No way that happens.
你也不敢在我身上下注吗
You don't think I'm a good bet?
跟那个无关
That has nothing to do with it.
这原来还是你的案子呢
This was your case.
可我交给你来做制胜一击
And I gave it to you to win.
这我能够胜任  只要你给我点信心
Which I will do if you just show some faith in me.
信心可以给你
You can have my faith,
但钱不能
But you're not getting my money.
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
我给你留了三条信息了
I left you three messages.
是路易陷害你  我们可以拿下他
Louis framed you. We can take him down.
我不想拿下他  迈克
I don't want to take him down, Mike.
为什么
Why not?
因为我想重新开始
Because I want a fresh start.
那你不想在皮尔逊・哈德曼律所工作了吗
So you don't wanna work at Pearson-Hardman anymore?
我已经在韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所面试了
I applied for a job at Wakefield-Cady.
他们当场就录用我了
They offered it to me in the room.
我周一上班
I start Monday.
你跑去那里工作
You took a job at the company
他们手里有泄露名单啊
that ended up with the leaked list?
你知道这看上去像什么吗
Do you know what that looks like?
我才不在乎呢
I don't care what it looks like.
我没做错什么  我还需要工作
I'm not guilty, and I need a job.
这么说你凡事都要知难而退
So the going gets rough, and you just quit?
我不是主动离开的  我是被解雇了
No, I'm not quitting. I was fired, remember?
不  你被停职了
No, you were suspended,
你还能保住你的工作
And you could still save your job.
路易想撵我走  我也不强留
If Louis wants me gone, I'm gone.
瑞秋  路易还陷害过我
Rachel, Louis tried to frame me once,
而我还击了
And I fought back.
你为什么不能这样呢
Why aren't you doing the same thing?
因为除了你
Because except for you,
皮尔逊・哈德曼律所再没第二个人关心我
no one from Pearson-Hardman has contacted me at all.
我为什么还要拼命留在那儿
Why would I fight to stay there?
他们说我泄露机密
They're accusing me of spilling secrets?
我就泄露一个给他们瞧瞧
I'll show 'em spilling secrets.
我会把一切都告诉韦克菲尔德・凯蒂律所
I'll tell Wakefield-Cady everything.
我做不到过目不忘  迈克
I may not have a photographic memory, Mike,
但我也知道不少
but I sure as hell know a lot.
瑞秋
Rachel.
钱班尔[007电影里M夫人的秘书]
Moneypenny.
-别那么喊我  -为什么
- Don't call me that. - Why not?
因为她喜欢他[邦德]
Because she had a thing for him.
我们正好相反
This is the other way around.
你不喜欢我吗
You don't like me?
不喜欢你还会给你这个吗
Like you enough to give you this.
这是什么
What's that?
我窃听了爱默生石油公司的电话
I tapped the phones at Emerson Petroleum.
这是特拉维斯・坦纳和几位
This is a conference call between Travis Tanner
爱默生高管之间的电话会议
and several high-ranking Emerson executives.
希望他们除了天气还聊别的了
I hope they're talking about more than just the weather.
他们还谈坦纳胁迫你客户的事了
They're talking about Tanner intimidating your client.
你我都心知肚明  没有搜查令
Both you and I know that without a warrant
这通录音是不被法庭接受的
this recording's not admissible in court.
如果你作证说录音来源不明就可以了
It is if you testify that you don't know where it came from.
你为什么这么帮我
Why'd you do this?
因为你需要
Because you need it.
我不会为了赢得案子而作伪证的
I'm not gonna commit perjury to win a case.
好奇怪啊  看我找到了什么
Oh, weird, look what I found.
你真是一群黑脸胖子里的白马王子
You are a prince among men.
我真不懂你为什么加脱脂牛奶
I don't understand why you use skim milk
再放鲜奶油和糖
and then put whipped cream and sugar in it.
因为我加的是脱脂牛奶
Because I use skim milk,
所以我能放鲜奶油和糖
I can put whipped cream and sugar in it.
怎么了
What's wrong?
-我们能谈谈吗  -行啊
- Can we talk for a second? - Yeah.
上周路易从信息技术部
Last week Louis got Rachel's confidential code
拿到了瑞秋的内部密码
from the I.T. Department.
然后呢
And?
然后这就是铁证啊
And it's a smoking gun.
是他陷害了她
He's the one that set her up.
路易为什么要背叛公司啊
Why would Louis betray the firm?
我哪知道  或许他对没当上资深合伙人
I don't know, maybe he's still upset
一事还耿耿于怀
that he got passed over for senior partner
于是弃船告别前就泄露了名单
and leaked the list before he jumped ship.
迈克  路易万般不是  也不是叛徒
Mike, Louis is a lot of things, but he's not a traitor.
他流的是皮尔逊・哈德曼律所的血
That man bleeds Pearson-Hardman.
他这会儿大概
He's probably wearing
就穿着皮尔逊・哈德曼律所 的内裤呢
Pearson-Hardman underwear right now.
我跟他去过网球俱乐部
I went to the tennis club with him.
听我的  他不穿内裤的
Trust me, he doesn't wear underwear.
我也在乎瑞秋
I care about Rachel too.
但这不是路易干的
Louis didn't do this.
好吧
Okay.
还有  如果你再向我提及
And if you ever mention
路易穿什么内衣
Louis' underwear situation to me again--
是你提起来的
You're the one that brought it up.
-消失  -遵命
- Go. - Okay.
共有74名原告
74 plaintiffs.
真不敢相信他们会为了两万五屈服
I can't believe they're willing to cave for $25,000.
别着急
Slow down.
我们得想办法击败坦纳
We need to figure out how to beat Tanner.
我一直被这家伙牵着鼻子走
Guy's been a step ahead of me this entire time.
-原因很明显嘛  -什么原因
- It's pretty obvious why. - Why?
你跟我说你知道他会去找肯尼
You told me that you knew he'd go to Kenny
是因为换了你也会这么做
because that's what you'd do,
前提是你愿意做出格的事的话
if you were willing to go out of bounds.
你是通过想你自己的招数来预测他的脚步
You anticipated him by thinking about what you'd do.
继续说
And?
而他也是这么预测你的
And that's exactly what he's doing to you.
或许你想走在这家伙前面
Maybe the only way to get ahead of this guy
就得想想你不会做什么
is to, I don't know, think about what you wouldn't do.
出其不意  这点子好
Surprise myself. I like that.
不客气
You're welcome.
你想告诉我你有什么打算吗
You wanna tell me what you're doing?
不要
Nope.
这对想出这个点子的人不太公平啊
Doesn't seem fair to the person whose idea it was.
我对空气弹琴呢
You're gone.
-你想跟我谈  说吧  -我是想谈
- You wanted to talk, talk. - I did.
我想把我们之间的争斗放下
I want to put this competition aside,
就算我们平手
call it a draw.
打退堂鼓了  哈维
Tapping out, Harv?
那个不是重点
This isn't about that.
这些活生生的人才是重点
This is about real people.
你给他们个合理的出价
You make them a reasonable offer,
我会让他们接受的
I'll get them to take it.
活生生的人
Real people?
你穿着一万二的西装站在那儿
You're standing there in a $12,000 suit
指使我消极怠工
asking me not to do my job.
你那么关心活生生的人
You care so much about those real people,
那就把你的午饭钱给他们吧
I suggest you give them your lunch money
但别来要我的
but don't ask me for mine.
凡妮莎  我到底还是需要那盘窃听带
Vanessa, I'm gonna need that wiretap after all.
-还有咖啡吗  -最后一杯
- Is there any more of that? - Last cup.
-那你煮...  -没
- Did you make-- - Nope.
老兄  这是基本礼貌
Dude, that's common courtesy.
你喝完一壶  就再煮一点
You finish a pot, you make another one.
我不做你要去找路易打小报告吗
You gonna turn me into Louis if I don't?
让我也被炒了
Hmm? Get me fired too?
迈克
Michael.
本杰明  你有东西给我吗
Benjamin, you got something for me?
愿赌服输  公平合理
Wager's a wager, fair is fair.
这是你的GX-9000
Here's your GX-9000.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
你用它看毛片  我会知道的
Use it for porn, and I'll know.
好奇怪
Weird.
路易  你好啊
Hey, Louis, how you doing?
本杰明刚刚为什么叫你路易
Why did Benjamin just call you Louis?
不知道  叫错了吧
I don't know. Made a mistake.
他没叫错
No, he didn't.
他叫你路易因为他认为你就是路易
He called you Louis because he thinks you are Louis.
是你谎称自己是路易
Because you posed as Louis
骗取瑞秋的员工代码
to get Rachel's employee code,
不是吗
didn't you?
听着  迈克  事实不是你想的那样
Look, Mike, it's not what you think.
事实就是如此
It's exactly what I think.
如实交待吧  吉米
Go on. Start talking, Jimmy,
不然我叫上本杰明
or I'll get get Benjamin
我们一起去见杰西卡
and we can all go see Jessica together.
听着
Listen,
韦克菲尔德・凯蒂答应让我做初级合伙人
Wakefield Cady offered me a junior partnership
只要我泄露证人名单
if I leaked the witness list.
迈克  听我说
No, no, listen, Mike.
因为上法学院我背了一身债
I have huge law school debts.
这点你肯定能明白
Okay? I mean, don't you?
我没法坐等皮尔逊・哈德曼
I can't wait for Pearson Hardman
升我做合伙人
to make me a partner.
那你还待在这儿做什么
So what are you still doing here then?
我把名单交给他们后
After I gave them the list,
他们反悔了
they reneged on the offer.
世事难料
Big surprise.
还真没想到他们会用这招
I didn't see that one coming.
别告发我  迈克  求你了
Just don't turn me in, Mike, please.
我家境贫寒
I came from nothing.
拼死拼活才上了哈佛法学院
I worked my ass off to get into Harvard Law
好不容易成为这儿的律师
and become an associate here.
你知道谁也一样拼死拼活吗
You know who else worked their ass off?
瑞秋・赞恩  因为你的所作所为
Rachel Zane, the paralegal who got fired
而被解雇的律师助理
because of what you did.
我并不知道用的她的代码
I didn't know it was her code.
只是需要使用些号码  兄弟
I just needed some numbers, man.
我没想到会被发现
I didn't think I was gonna get caught.
迈克  我犯了个错误
Look, Mike, I made one mistake.
好吗
Okay?
难道你不曾铤而走险
I mean, haven't you ever cut some corners,
做出后悔的事吗
done some things you regretted?
吉米  我并不是针对你  好吗
Jimmy, I like you, man, okay?
但要还瑞秋清白
But to clear Rachel's name,
必须让他们知道内奸另有其人
they have to know she wasn't the one.
如果你主动承认
If you come forward,
他们顶多解雇你
maybe they fire you.
可如果你是被我告发的
If I turn you in,
这就永远是你职业生涯中的污点
it's gonna follow you for the rest of your career.
你自己决定
It's up to you.
哈维  我想帮你一个忙
Harvey, I'm gonna do you a favor.
为何不让迈克・罗斯出去散个步
Why don't you tell Mike Ross to take a hike?
他可以待着
He can stay.
好的
Okay.
你的原告中有九十五人
You see, 95 of your plaintiffs
已经打过电话咨询和解的情况
have already called me about the settlement.
其他人明白利害关系
It's just a matter of time
也只是早晚而已
before the rest of them see the light.
我赢了
I win.
我不知道你这信息是什么时候的
I don't know the last time you checked,
但据我所知  今天早上
but as of this morning
我的两百名原告依然坚持诉讼到底
all 200 of my plaintiffs are staying with me.
胡扯
Bullshit.
我给他们预支了一笔胜过和解的金额
I got them an advance against their settlement.
没有哪家正常的金融机构
No finance company in their right mind
会给你的诉讼做担保
will back your suit.
我不知道耶鲁是否有教你数学
I don't know if they taught you math at Yale,
但这可是五百万
but that's 5 million.
每名原告两万五美金
$25,000 a plaintiff.
正是你们收买他们的金额
Exactly what you tried to buy them off for.
你知道这意味着什么吗
You know what this means?
我会逐一对付他们
I'm gonna hammer them all one by one,
个个击破  索性大家都撕破脸
break them down, and it's gonna get ugly.
不  你不会
No, you're not.
这是什么
What the hell is that?
你和爱默生石油公司讨论如何派人
It's a conversation between you and Emerson Petroleum
恐吓肯尼・沃达斯科的谈话
discussing how you sent a man to intimidate Kenny Verdasco.
听听吧
Take a listen.
放心  不会让你患上癌症
Don't worry, it's not gonna give you cancer.
不管这是什么
No matter what that is,
都是法庭不允许采纳的物证
it's not admissible.
除非当然  你有搜查令  而你没有
Unless of course you had a warrant, which you didn't.
家门前捡到的
Showed up on my doorstep.
我写了宣誓书以证明它的真实性
And I declared that in this affidavit
并将呈送法庭
which I'm about to send to court.
你作伪证
So you're gonna perjure yourself
就是为了赢这案子吗
just to win this case?
不  我不会作伪证
No, I'm not gonna perjure myself.
即使我要作
Even if I were,
也不会就为了赢这件案子
it wouldn't be just to win this case.
而是要你身陷囹圄
It'd be to get your ass thrown in jail.
你有律师代理权
See, you have power of attorney,
你会接受这项协议
and you're gonna accept this settlement,
每名原告两百万美金
$2 million a plaintiff.
你不得不接受
You're gonna take it.
然后带着你的谄媚嘴脸
And you and that shit eating grin
滚回波士顿
are gonna fly back to boston
从我的地盘上永远消失
and never come back to my town again.
你可以用我的
You can use mine.
说了他会签名
Told you I'd get his autograph.
真想不到
I can't believe you.
你居然会为了赢案子而作伪证
You were gonna perjure yourself just to win.
我以为你是有底线的
I thought you didn't cross lines.
而这正是你和他那种人的区别所在
That's the difference between guys like you and him.
我根本不会提交这份宣誓书
I had no intention of submitting this affidavit.
我不需要作伪证
I'm not gonna perjure myself,
但是坦纳不知道
but Tanner doesn't know that,
他也绝不会知道
and he never will.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为喜欢不按规矩办事的人
Because a man who's willing to break the rules
无法想象别人也不按规矩
can't imagine someone else wouldn't.
你说你是接受我的建议
You said that you took my advice
结果令你自己也很惊讶
and that you surprised yourself.
没错
I did.
为原告们申请的那笔贷款
That loan I got for the plaintiffs,
我自己先砸了一百万美金才拿到的
I put up a million dollars of my own money to get it.
如果这还不叫动感情
If that's not having emotion,
那我不知道情为何物了
I don't know what is.
-走开  -听着有点生气哈
- Get out. - That seemed a little angry.
开心  满意  还是高兴
Feeling good? Satisfied? Happy?
好吧
All right.
动情了
Emotional.
好吧  也许是有点开心
Okay, maybe a little happy.
两百万美金
$2 million?
不是告诉过你他可是我的得力干将吗
Didn't I tell you he was my right hand?
-我不知道该说什么  -无需多言
- I don't know what to say. - Don't say anything.
我只想知道大伙儿听到你的好消息后
Tell me what it's like
高兴的表情
when you deliver this news to everyone.
谢谢你
Thank you.
说了我会赢
Told you I'd win.
对你也是好事
And it's a good thing too.
因为你要是输了...
Because if you hadn't, oh...
什么
What, oh?
那一百万美金可没法报销
There's no way we're gonna cover that million dollars.
-都不能吗  -不行
- None of it? - Nope.
你的肩膀怎么样了
Hey, how's your shoulder?
再好不过
Amazing.
你找我吗
You called me?
当然
Sure did.
请坐
Have a seat.
我喜欢站着
I prefer to stand.
也好
Fair enough.
我犯了个错误
Uh, I made a mistake.
你平白无故受罚
You were unfairly punished,
而我想正式
and I would like to officially
欢迎你回到公司
just welcome you back.
-谢谢  -不用谢
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
你开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
你觉得我会这么容易放过你吗
You think I'm gonna make it that easy on you?
我要加薪
I want a raise.
-百分之三  -百分之十
- 3%. - 10%.
-百分之七  -百分之十
- 7%. - 10%.
行
Fine.
而且如果我决定上法学院
And Pearson Hardman pays for law school
皮尔逊・哈德曼会报销学费
when I decide to go.
同意
Agreed.
还有一件事
And one more thing.
这本该是我走进来时
This should've been the first words out of your mouth
你说的第一句话
when I walked in here.
你现在得向我道歉
You need to apologize to me right now,
不然我明早一来
or I'm gonna file a lawsuit
就让你吃官司
against you first thing in the morning.
没错
You're right.
我是该道歉
I should have apologized.
但你威胁不了我
But don't you threaten me.
我严格按程序办事
I followed procedure to the letter,
你没理由诉讼
and you have no basis for a lawsuit.
不  我是没有
No, I don't.
这件事是没有
Not about this.
但如果你认为我来公司的这些年
But if you don't think I have a basis
你干的那摊烂事我一点把柄都没有的话
for all the shit you've pulled over the years I've been here,
那么请再想想
Think again.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
行了吧
Okay?
情况如何
How'd it go?
我不知道你今晚是否有安排
I don't know if you had plans tonight,
但你必须取消安排来帮我
but you're gonna cancel and help me put
收拾办公室
my office back together.
没问题
Sure thing.
只要你别又逢难而退
So long as you don't quit halfway through.
谢谢你  迈克
Thank you, Mike.
不用客气
Yeah, sure thing.
这个东西要放哪
So, where does this go?
那边
Over there.